美国米高梅影片公司
美国哥伦比亚影片公司 出品
死而
死而复生
墨西哥城
亡灵节
我说你是不是快等不及了
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
去去就来
I won't be long.
欢迎 亲爱的斯奇亚拉先生
旅途还愉快吗？
带来了吗？
带来了 在那儿呢
什么时候炸体育馆？
下午六点钟
那么离开所乘的飞机呢？
全都安排好了
之后有什么安排？
之后啊 我就去拜访“幽冥国王”
来干一杯 我的朋友
敬亡灵！
那我先干为敬
Bottoms up.
在广场碰头
Meet me at the square!
丹尼尔·克雷格
饰演伊恩·弗莱明笔下的007詹姆斯邦德
007：幽灵党
里斯托弗·瓦尔兹
莱亚·西多克斯
本·威士肖
娜奥米·哈里斯
戴夫·巴蒂斯塔
安德鲁·斯科特
罗里·金尼尔
加斯帕·克里斯滕森
莫妮卡·贝鲁奇
拉尔夫·费因斯
联合制片人
丹尼尔·克雷格
安德鲁·诺克斯
大卫·波普
服装
贾妮·特米米
剪辑
李·史密斯
摄影
霍伊特·范·霍伊特玛
美术设计
丹尼斯·加斯内尔
音乐
托马斯·纽曼
执行制片人
卡伦姆·麦克道格尔
编剧
约翰·洛根 尼尔·普尔维斯 罗伯特·魏德 杰兹·巴特沃兹
故事
约翰·洛根 尼尔·普尔维斯 罗伯特·魏德
制片人
迈克尔·威尔森 芭芭拉·布鲁克利
导演
萨姆·门德斯
墨西哥惨剧
想从哪儿就从哪说起
Start anywhere you like.
你慢慢说 007 不过五分钟后
Take your time, 007. But in 5 minutes,
联合安全局的头儿会从那扇门走进来
the head of the joint security service is going to walk through that door
而我得向他解释 为什么我们的特工会一时兴起
and I got to explain to him, how one of our agents decided to porter off
独自去墨西哥晃悠 然后引发这场国际性事件
to Mexico all on his own and caused an international incident.
但无论怎么说 没有我们情况会更糟
With all due respect, sir, it could have been worse.
还不够糟？
Worse?
你把半条街炸飞了
You blew up half a bloody block.
半条街总比牺牲一体育馆的人强吧？
Well, better half a block than a whole stadium full of people.
那时你可没拍板的权力
You had no authority.
没有！
None.
你也知道 我们正经历
As you know, we're in the middle of the biggest
英国情报系统最大规模的改组
shake up in the history of British intelligence.
我们跟军情五处合并的文件还墨迹未干
The inks barely dry on this merger with MI5 and already they are itching for a chance
五处就盼着找个机会永远拿掉00项目 而你刚好成全了他们
to scrap the 00 program forever. And you just given them one.
你说的没错 今天你的日子不会好过
You are right, sir. You have got a tricky day ahead.
我现在是在严肃的问你
This is an official question.
那天在墨西哥城 你到底干什么去了？
Mexico city, what were you doing there?
我只是碰巧在度假 早该休的假正好想休了
It's just a coincidence. I was taking some overdue holiday.
那好 行吧
Okay. Fine.
从今天早上开始你被正式限制行动
As of this morning, you are officially grounded.
我决定无限期中止你所有的行动
I'm standing you down from all operations indefinitely.
很好啊 长官
Very good, sir.
您请讲
Sir?
我不管你在玩什么小把戏
I don't know what you are playing, but whatever it is
最好马上收手
it has to stop...
马上
now.
- 真对不住 打扰你们了吧？ - 哪有？
- So sorry, am I interrupting? - Not remotely.
007 这位是麦克斯·登比 联合安全局的一把手
007, I'd like you to meet Max Denbigh, head of the joint security service.
终于见到007真身了 听说了不少事迹
Well, it's a pleasure to finally meet you, 007. I heard a lot about you.
- 大部分是好事 - 祝贺你新官走马上任
- Most of it is good. - Congratulations on your new appointment.
- 谢谢了 - 现在能叫你C先生了吧？
Thank you. Suppose we should call you C, now.
- 不 叫我麦克斯就行了 - 我还是叫你C好了 C
- No, no. Max, please. - No, I think I'll call you, C.
- C - 随你便了
- C. - As you wish.
我们的门永远敞开 007 随时欢迎我的下属
Well, my door is always open, 007 for my employees.
这次合并掀开了新篇章
This merger is going to be a whole new chapter for us.
我们要带领英国情报系统走出黑暗时代 重见天日
We're going to bring British intelligence out of the dark ages into the light.
- 听起来相当不错 - 就这样 007
- That all sounds lovely. - That will be all, 007.
明天向Q报到体检 谢谢
Report to Q tomorrow for medical, thank you.
好的 长官
Very good, sir.
詹姆斯
James.
莫尼彭尼
Moneypenny.
- 我说 会开得怎么样？ - 挺好的 谢谢
- So, how was the meeting? - Very good, thank you.
给你 法医终于把这个解禁了
Here, forensics finally released this.
这是什么？
What is it?
是从天幕庄园抢救出的私人物品
It's personal effects they recovered from Sky-fall.
太好了 待会儿再给我捎来吧
Perfect. You can bring it to me later.
- 你什么意思？ - 9点钟送到我家来
- What do you mean? - My place, 9 o'clock.
- 晚上好 - 请进
- Evening. - Come in.
你才搬进来吗？
Have you just moved in?
不是啊
No.
你这套布置我挺喜欢
Well, I like what you've done with the place.
你的档案
Your delivery.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 要不要喝一杯？ - 算了我又不过夜
- Would you like a drink? - No, thanks. I'm not staying.
那可惜了
It's a shame.
怎么回事 詹姆斯？
What's going on, James?
现在军情六处没有人不在讨论这事儿
There's not one person in MI6 who isn't talking about it.
他们在讨论什么事啊 你说说
Talking about what, exactly?
他们说你在墨西哥这次做的过火了
That what you did in Mexico was one step too far.
还说你玩完了
That you're finished.
-你怎么看？ - 我恰恰觉得你好戏才开场
- What do you think? - I think you're just getting started.
- 我不明白你的意思 - 好吧
- I don't know what you mean. - Fine
我猜你手头有个秘密
I think you've got a secret.
而且你跟谁都不想说
And it's something you won't tell anyone.
因为你谁都不相信
Because you don't trust anyone.
我若有什么不测 007 我需要你做件事
If anything happens to me for some reason. I need you to you to do something.
找一个男的 他叫叫马科·斯奇亚拉
Find a man called Marco Sciarra.
干掉他 然后别错过他的葬礼
Kill him. And don't miss the funeral.
- 我的老天 你从哪儿弄到的？ - 她刚死就发到了我的邮箱
- Jesus! Where did you get it? - From my mailbox just after she died.
她总能出乎人意料
She was never short of surprises.
即便是死亡也阻挡不了她的工作
Wasn't gonna let death get in the way of her job.
-而我也开始跟踪斯奇亚拉 - 那你查到什么了？
- I've been tracking Sciarra ever since. - And what have you found?
还没有什么重大发现
Nothing significant, yet.
- 他葬礼是哪天？ - 三天之后 在罗马举行
- When's the funeral? - Three days. In Rome.
你要是指望M会批准你去 那你真是疯了
If you think M's signing off for that, you're insane!
- 他不会让你离开半步的 - 是的 这也算是个小麻烦
- He won't let you out of his sight. - Yes, that's a bit of a problem.
听我说 能不能暗地里帮我挖挖情报去？
Listen, could you do a little quiet digging for me?
我在墨西哥听到一个名字 "冥王"
I heard a name in Mexico, The Pale King.
你要我给你当卧底吗？
You want me to be your mole!
没错
Yes.
你凭什么认为我值得信任？
What makes you think you can trust me?
直觉
Instinct.
临时监护令
ORDER of TEMPORARY GUARDIANSHIP.
可怜的老楼
Poor old girl.
已经计划被拆除了
Rigged the demolition in a week.
- 拆了比修复重建要省钱 - 也是
Cheaper to knock her down, than to rebuild.
光阴脚步匆匆 谁都不等
Still, "Iron waits for no man" and all that.
对了 钱都花到这上面来了
Anyway, all the money's been spent on this.
国家安全中心的新大楼
The New Center for National Security!
- 这不就是C的新巢穴嘛？ - 你见过他了吗？
- So, that's C's new digs. - You've met him, have you?
- 昨天见过 这人什么来头？ - 典型的中央政府高级官僚
- Yesterday, what do we know about it? - Perfect Whitehall Mandarin.
去年写了份材料 说00项目已经过时了
Wrote a dossier last year about how the 00 program was obsolete.
说无人机可以代劳海外那些龌龊活儿
How drones could do our dirty work abroad.
- 他跟内政大臣还是同学 - 果不其然
- Went to school with our Home Secretary. - Of course he did!
这次合并只是开了个头
This murder's just the start of it.
三天后在东京有个会议
Three days, there's a security conference in Tokyo
将决定新的世界秩序
to decide the New World Order.
若能说动各方
If he gets his ways,
他就有权无限制地获取
He'll have unlimited access to the combined intelligence streams
9个国家的情报
of nine countries.
- 当然也包括我们 - 不错
- Including us. - Right.
你不在的时候发生了许多事
Well, lots happened when you were away.
汉堡发生列车爆炸
Train bombing in Hamburg
突尼斯发生工厂爆炸
and an industrial explosion in Tunisia.
现在这时机对我们不利 全是在帮C的忙啊
Not great timing for us, we're rather playing into C's hands.
而M 我猜他也感受到压力了
M, well, let's say he's feeling the pressure.
对 我发现了
Yeah, I've noticed.
这边来 007 留神啊 脚底有点滑滑
This way, 007. Be careful, it's quite slippery.
合并之后 Q在高官们面前觉得不太自在
Q wasn't exactly feeling at home in Whitehall up with the new merger so,
所以在这儿另行开张 躲开那些烦人的眼线
He set up a shop here, away from prying eyes as it were.
听说他为你设计了特别的东西
I hear he's get something rather special planned for you.
我都迫不及待了
I can hardly wait.
-007 - 你好 Q
- Ah, 007. - Q.
抱歉 我这里太乱
Please excuse the mess. Lots of things were a
一切都还在变 还没尘埃落定呢
little bit up in the air with the changes and all.
有几样东西要给你看
Couple of things to get through.
咱们先干正事吧
Shall we get started?
放松就好
Just relax.
对 就这样
That's it, lovely.
- 现在你会觉得有些 - 老天爷啊！
- Now, you may feel a small... - Christ!
刺痛感
Prick.
- 这是什么？ - 最前沿的纳米技术
- What is it? - Cutting edge nano technology.
"智能血液" 是血管里的微型芯片
Smart Blood. Microchips in your bloodstream.
可以帮我们定位你在外的活动
Allows us to track your movements in the field.
看到这些读数了吗？
You see those read-outs?
在地球任何角落都能测到你的生命体征
We can monitor your vital signs from anywhere on the planet.
这个实在太棒了
This is marvelous
算是墨西哥事件后的保险措施 M直接指示要搞的
I call it the Post-Mexico insurance policy, by direct order then.
这我完全能理解
I completely understand.
很好
Good.
好吧 我这里还有 还有最后一样东西 你看完就能走了
Well I've just um... One last thing and you could be on your way.
不是一般的气派吧？
Magnificent isn't she?
起步加速到60迈只需3.2秒
0 to 60 in 3.2 seconds.
全车身防弹 还深藏各种绝技
Fully bulletproof, few little tricks up her sleeve.
只可惜她本来是你的 但现在
Shame really, she was meant for you but she...
她配给009使用了
been reassigned to 009.
不过这个你可以有
But you can have this.
- 能派上大用场吗？ - 会报时是肯定的
- Does it do anything? - It tells the time.
能帮你变得更加守时
Might cope with your punctuality issue.
- M的主意吧？ - 你猜对了
- M's idea? - Precisely.
要提醒你一句
Oh, one word of warning.
这表的闹铃动静相当大 你应该懂我的意思
The alarm is rather loud. If you know what I mean.
我想是的
Like I do?
对了
Oh, yes.
这个老家伙得花不少时间呢
That odd thing is taking quite a bit of time.
它大部分已经没法用了 就方向盘还好使
Mind you there wasn't much left to work on. Only a steering wheel.
我记得告诉过你要带回一整台车 不是带回一台车架
I believe I said "Bring it back in one piece", not "Bring back one piece."
那好吧 好好享受假期吧 007
Anyway, enjoy your downtime, 007.
- Q - 怎么了？
- Q. - Yes?
既然你现在能对我的所有行踪都了如指掌
Well now you know exactly where I am, all the time.
那能不能帮我个忙？
Would you do something for me?
你脑子里在想什么呢？
What do you have in mind exactly?
能帮我消失吗？
Make me disappear.
唔 我提醒你一下 我现在直接对M负责
Um, may I remind you. That I answer directly to M.
我有一套按揭要还 还养了两只猫
I also have a mortgage and 2 cats to feed.
哦
Oh.
所以我建议你最好先相信我
Then I suggest you trust me.
哪怕是为了那两只猫呢
Think of the cats.
很高兴见到你 007 真的
Well it's lovely to see you, 007. Lovely.
我要提醒你 目前这个智能血液 它显然还处于开发阶段
No, I'm meant to tell you.
所以我们也会偶尔遇到
The Smart Blood program is still in its developmental phrase.
头24小时接收不到信号的情况
So, we may experience the odd drop in coverage during the first 24 hours.
其实48小时内 即便部署了也会有失灵 不过在那之后就应该完全没问题了
48 hours after administration. After that it should work perfectly.
- 我会给你寄明信片的 - 求你别这样
- I'll send you a postcard. - Please don't.
谢谢你
詹姆斯
Thank you J.
- 早上好 那是什么？ - 一个追求者送的礼物而已
- Morning, what's that? - Oh, just something from an admirer.
- 今天不是你生日吧？ - 不是 长官
-Is today your birthday? - No, sir.
人家上周才过生日
That was last week.
- 早啊 - 009已经到了 要来那辆提DB10跑车
Morning, 009 has arrived to pick up the DB10, sir.
- 他在楼上等你呢 - 好的 行 先这样
- He's waiting upstairs. - Oh, good. Yes. Fine.
这下子好了
Shit.
罗马
悼词
Sign of hope in the resurrection
还请夫人节哀顺变
I'm sorry for your loss.
- 你认识我丈夫吗？ - 只简单打过照面
- You knew my husband? - Only briefly.
- 你是做什么的？ - 人寿保险
- What did you do? - Life insurance.
- 可惜你来的有点晚 - 对于您丈夫是晚了
- Probably too late for that. - For your husband, yes.
- 不过对您来说呢 - 对我？
- What about you? - Me?
我听说一些寡妇在失去丈夫之后不久就会意外丧命
I hear the life expectancy of some widows can be very short.
你怎么可以这么说你？没看见我还在悲伤中吗？
How can you talk like this? Can't you see I'm grieving?
没有
No.
- 多美妙的景致啊 - 你这是在浪费时间
- What a lovely view. - You're wasting your time.
还有一百多人会追杀我的
There are a hundred more that would come after me.
你这只是帮我 活五分钟而已
All you buy me, is 5 minutes.
真是难得 该来喝一杯了
Excellent, time for a drink.
是你杀了他 没说错吧？
You killed him, didn't you?
- 你杀了我丈夫 - 他本身就是杀手
- My husband. - He was an assassin.
相信我 他不会觉得我是私事公办
Trust me, he won't take it personally.
你这是亲手送我上断头台 我以前地位很高的
You signed my death warrant. I was respected.
- 你在忠于一个你恨人 - 他欣赏我的沉默
- Loyal to a man you hated. - He trusted my silence.
现在他走了 我也玩完了 我谁都不会相信
With him gone, I'm a dead woman. I can trust nobody.
- 我很了解这种感受 - 那我就告诉你 我不信任你
I know the feeling well - Well, I can tell you the victim tries to...
- 这说明你的直觉相当的准 - 你要是不马上离开 我们都会丧命的
Then you have impeccable instincts - If you don't leave now, we'll die together
这可比别的死法痛快多了
I can think of worse ways to go.
我看你简直是是疯了 你叫什么？
Then you're obviously crazy, Mr...
邦德
Bond.
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.
我说的那些人啊 你可不知道他们的做派
These people... If you just knew what they could do.
他们能耐非常大
The power they have.
你丈夫有没有提及过"冥王"
Did you ever heard him mention The Pale King?
没有
No.
那个神秘的组织
The organization.
成员几乎很少见面
They hardly ever meet.
但由于我丈夫出了那么大的事
But because what happened to my husband.
-  他们今晚要开会 - 为什么？
- They meet tonight. - Why?
- 要挑选出替补的人 - 在哪儿？
- To choose a replacement. - Where?
在卡登撒华彩宫
La Pallazzo Cadenzza.
- 9点开始 - 估计很有看头 我没准会去看看
- At nine. - Sounds like fun, I might drop by.
他整个人都陷进去了
He was obsessed.
他耗在那里的时间比陪我的都要多
Spend more time with them than with me.
那这个男的可真不聪明
Then, that man was a fool.
不留个电话号码？
Leaving your number?
我找了一个美国朋友 叫费利克斯
I'm calling an American friend of mine, Felix.
他会联系美国大使馆带你离开的
I'll contact his embassy, get you out of here.
保证你的安全
You'll be safe.
詹姆斯 别走
Don't go, James.
你不能去那儿 那可是个杀人不眨眼的地方
If you go there, you're crossing over to a place where there is no mercy
我必须得走
I have to go.
祝你好运 亲爱的露西亚
Good luck, Mrs. Lucia.
嘿 要上哪儿去啊？
Hey, wait there.
还不亮明身份 你这混蛋
-你是谁啊？ - 我是米老鼠呀 你是谁？
请进吧
Sorry.
在线购药网站提供了很好的新销售平台
...pharmacy sites has provided an excellent new sales platform.
我们将许多网站改造成未批准药物的交易场所
We have adapted many of them into clearinghouses for unapproved drugs.
除此之外 最新的数据显示
In addition to which, the latest figures show that presently
我们已控制了70%的抗疟疾疫苗
control 70% of antimalarial vaccines.
34%的艾滋病药物和40%肿瘤药物 在撒哈拉以南的市场
34% on HIV and 40% of all ontological drug across Sub-Saharan Africa.
但是 世界卫生组织真是跟我们过不去
We've faced challenges from the WHO and their campaign
他们正在打击我们所谓的仿冒药品
against our counterfeit pharmaceuticals.
我们已经锁定需要处理的关键人物
We have now identified the key individuals to target.
希望能像人口贩卖委员会那次一样成功
We expect the same success as we had against the Council of Union Traffic.
沃格尔博士
Dr. Vogel.
在委员会全体请辞后
我们已将16万女移民安排进休闲性产业
而接近完成的"九只眼"全球监控倡议
意味着我们将拥有独一无二的监视能力
而现在到了该强势扩张的时候了
这绝对是个好消息
别让我打断你们了
Don't let me interrupt you.
这绝对是个好消息
我们得到增强的监控能力
意味着来自政府情报机构的阻力
将被轻而易举化解
我们赢定了
谢谢你 博士
Thank you, Doctor.
现在来处理手头上的事项
Now, onto the matter at hand.
在我们成功实施汉堡和突尼斯的袭击之后
After our successful attack in Hamburg and Tunisia.
在墨西哥城的袭击被迫中止
We abort an attack on Mexico City and
而我们杰出的的同事马科·斯奇亚拉不幸身亡
the death of our valued colleague, Marco Sciarra.
他身后留下了一项未完成的使命
Leave one of his duty, outstanding.
格拉先生 "冥王"必须被处理掉
Se?or Gerard, the Pale King must be terminated.
你可否去趟奥尔陶斯？
Will you make the journey to Attersee?
当然可以
我是绝对忠于组织的
我这份忠诚至死不渝
绝不会再有
业余之举
绝不会再示弱
在座有没有哪位反对格拉先生接任这个席位？
Does anyone challenge Se?or Guerra for this position?
欢迎你
Welcome.
请陈述你能接任斯奇亚拉的理由
State your credentials for succeeding, Se?or Guerra.
真有意思
It's funny.
墨西哥那次宛如钟声勾起了我遥远的记忆
All that excitement in Mexico City rang a distant bell.
而现在 就在今晚一刹那间 我突然就全明白了
And now, suddenly this evening it makes perfect sense.
欢迎你 詹姆斯
Welcome, James.
真是好久不见了 但我们最终还是再会了
It's been a long time. But finally here we are!
你怎么才来？
What took you so long?
布 谷
Cuckoo.
再见了 米老鼠
Ciao, Mickey Mouse!
这不是跟我闹着玩儿吗
Are you kidding me?
不会吧
No!
脑子有病啊！
What are you doing?
呼叫莫尼彭尼
Moneypenny.
- 邦德？ - 听着 莫尼彭尼
- Bond? - Listen, Moneypenny.
汉堡 突尼斯和墨西哥袭击是相互关联的
Hamburg, Tunisia, Mexico City, they're all linked.
是同一个组织策划的连环袭击
It's one organization coordinating multiple attacks.
- 看来她说的没错 - 她(M夫人)就没错过
- So she was right. - Of course she was.
- 我查过了 - 谁打来的？
- I ran that check. - Who is it?
是我老板 他信用卡被偷了 不是大事
My boss had his credit card stolen, it's nothing.
- 你赶紧先睡去吧 - 别弄太久啊
- Why don't you go back to sleep? - Don't be long.
- 谁在那儿？ - 没谁啊
- Who is that? - No one.
- 你没说实话 - 就一普通朋友
- No, it was. - It's just a friend.
- 大半夜还在你那儿？ - 生活就是这样 詹姆斯
At this time of night? It's called life, James.
有时你也该体验下
You should try it sometime.
那个"幽冥国王" 貌似是位你曾经交过手的人
The Pale King, it looks like you've had dealings with him before.
- 量子危机那次 - 果不其然 是怀特先生
- Quantum. - Of course, Mr. White!
就是他
That's him.
最近一次现身 是在奥地利的奥尔陶斯 四个月前的事了
Last unconfirmed sighting, Attersee in Austria. Four months ago.
你先等一下
Hope that's all.
- 还没挂吧？ - 没挂
- You still there? - Yeah.
- 我再报个名字行吗？ - 可以 说吧
- Run another name, will you? - Okay.
是个男的 叫弗朗兹·奥伯豪斯
A man called Franz Oberhauss.
查查他生前和死后的档案和行踪
Check his files, before and after his death.
怎么还有死后 什么意思？
After his death? What are you talking about?
拜托 你照办就是了
Please, just do it.
好的 Q 给我亮亮家伙
Okay, Q. Give me something.
真是越来越给劲了
That's more like it.
试试手气吧
Here goes nothing.
晚上好
Good evening.
不要听信他们减少监控的主张
Do not let them tell you, we need less surveillance.
相反要增加更多
We need more.
更加多
Much more.
我愿重申
I say again.
这个九只眼委员会将有权获得
The 9 Eyes Committee will have full access to the combined intelligence
所有成员国的情报信息流
streams of all member states.
数据越多分析得越透彻
More data, more analysis.
发生恐怖袭击的可能性就会越低
Less likelihood of terrorist attacks.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
到了全世界安全机构联合起来的时候了
It's time for the security services of the world to unite.
各自为战 我们不堪一击
Alone, we are weak.
联合起来 我们汇聚全球力量
Together, we're a global power.
这肯定不走选举程序
An unelected one.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
谢谢
现在就方案进行表决
We will now vote on the resolution.
女士们先生们 请开始投票
Ladies and gentlemen, please cast your votes.
结果是八票赞成一票反对
The vote is 8 to 1 in favour.
但是如各位所知 只有全票赞成才能通过决议
However, as you know. We cannot proceed unless the unanimous vote.
因此 九只眼议案未能获得通过
The 9 Eyes notion, is therefore, not passed.
这就是民主啊
Democracy.
感谢女士们先生们 今晚的会议现在休会
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. This evening session is adjourned.
(我们能否确定邦德就在伦敦？)
ARE WE SURE BOND'S IN LONDON?
- 长官您好 - 拜托请告诉我007就在伦敦
- Yes, sir. - Please tell me 007 is in London.
是的 我那个
Oh, yes. Um.
现在先让我看一下
I'll just take a look now, sir.
因为他要是不在 你丫麻烦就大了
Because if he isn't, you're in deep shit.
我TM就给你10秒钟时间
You've get precisely, 10 seconds.
找到了 长官 他应该是在切尔西
I have him, sir. He appears to be in Chelsea.
给我盯死了 等我回来 明白吗？
Well, I want eyes on him when I get back. Understood?
我完全明白您的意思 长官
I completely understand... Sir..
帮我个忙行吗？ 下手要快点儿
Do me a favour, make it quick.
到楼上来 怀特先生
Upstairs, Mr. White.
我知道死神会以一张熟悉的面孔前来索命 但没想到会是你
I always knew death would wear a familiar face but not yours.
我为何会有此等荣幸啊 邦德先生？
So watch over this place here, Mr. Bond.
最近我参加了一场会议
I was at a meeting recently.
然后出现了你的名字
And your name came up.
很荣幸伦敦方面还在讨论我
I'm flattered London is still talking about me.
那不是军情六处的会 是在罗马开的
It wasn't MI6. It was Rome.
是你的组织 不是我的
Your team, not mine.
上个月 我在手机里发现了剧毒的金属铊(放射性有毒金属元素)
Last month, I found Thallium in my cell phone.
他真是不辱使命
It's done its job.
我就剩几个星期了 没准还短点
I have a few weeks. Maybe less.
所以说真是缘分啊 邦德先生
So, here we are, Mr. Bond.
两个将死之人一起共度良宵
Two dead men enjoying the evening.
- 你到底干了什么？ - 我没有听他的命令
- What did you do? - I disobeyed them.
我曾竭尽全力追随他 可是他变了
Followed him as far as I could and he... changed.
我明白了 你良心发现了
Oh, I see. You grew conscious.
咱们恩怨归恩怨 可这样
Our game is our game. But this...
干扯上女人 扯上儿童
women, children.
这金属铊起码说明他不再欣赏你了
Well, the Thallium would suggest he doesn't like you very much anymore.
而且你看他也是一样的
I'm clear that the feeling in mutual.
你还不如告诉我该怎样找到他
So, why don't you tell me how to find him again?
- 得了吧 - 告诉我他在哪儿
- Oh, come on! Tell me where he is.
他无处不在 无处不在
He's everywhere! Everywhere!
他堂而皇之地坐在你书桌前 他吻着你的女人
He's sitting at your desk, he's kissing with your
还和你家人淡定地共进晚餐
love or he's doing something with your family!
你是在掩护某个人吧？
You're protecting someone.
是你夫人吗？
Your wife?
她很久之前就不在了
She left long ago.
那是你的儿子？
Your son?
还是你女儿？
Your daughter.
你找不到她的 她相当聪明
You won't find her, she's clever.
她比我聪明 知道怎么躲起来
She's smarter than me, she knows how to hide.
说出那人在哪 我就能保护你女儿
I can protect her, if you tell me where he is.
- 我能保住她的命 - 好啊
- I can keep her alive. - Yeah?
- 我向你承诺 - 你向我承诺？
- You have my word. - Your word?!
一个杀手也能信？
The word of an assassin?
说到做到
That's my word.
"美国人" 你只要能救她
American. You save her.
她就能带你去"美国人"那儿 她非常了解
She can lead you to the American, she knows the American.
先去霍夫勒诊所看看
Try the Chauffeur Clinic.
你现在就是只风筝 在飓风中飞舞的风筝 邦德先生
You're a kite dancing in a hurricane, Mr. Bond.
永别了
So long!
你可真行 能让政府财政出钱为这个吐血买单
Can't deny I'm impressed you got HMG to cough up for all of us.
得了 政府哪有钱盖这种大楼啊
Good God, the government couldn't afford this kind of facility.
大部分还得靠私营企业的捐助
No, it was benefactor. Mostly from the private sector.
当正式运行了
When it goes online,
这栋楼将成为史上最强悍的
this building will be the most sophisticated
数据收集系统
data gathering system in history.
成为全天候主宰世界的数字幽灵
The World's digital ghost available 24/7
也是乔治·奥威尔的终极噩梦
George Orwell's worse nightmare.
你喜欢就好
I'm glad you like it.
九只眼未获全票通过真是遗憾
My commiseration on losing the 9 Eyes vote.
- 对你打击挺大吧 - 倒没什么
- Must have been a blow. - Not really.
南非方面想通也只是个时间问题
Only matter of time before South Africa sees the light and you know what they say,
而且罗马也不是一天建成的 可能用了一天半呢
Rome wasn't built in a day, a day and a half maybe.
我说麦克斯 我知道监控这事是日常必备
Look, Max. I know surveillance is fact of life.
但让我担心的是你使用情报的方式 以及谁会用这些情报
It's how you use the information that concerns me and who is using it.
这是保障公众安全所必须的
This is what we need to do to keep the people safe.
00项目已经过时了
00 Program is prehistoric.
现在你还能单靠一个特工就包打天下吗？
Come on, M. You can't tell me that one man in the field can compete with all of this.
有杀人执照也力不从心啊
Running around out there with his license to kill?
你有没有真正杀过人 麦克斯？
Have you ever had to kill a man, Max?
有吗？
Have you?
要心里有底 你才可以扣动扳机
To pull that trigger, you have to be strong.
是的 先要进行调查 要分析评估 锁定目标
Yes, you investigate, analyze, assess, target.
然后你要盯着对方的眼睛 接着做出判断
And then you have to look them in the eye and make the call.
那些个无人机 窃听器 摄像头 速记 以及所有现行的监控手段
And all the drones, bugs, cameras and all the surveillance in the world.
都不会告诉你下一步怎么办
Can't tell you what to do next.
一张杀人执照 也是一张不乱杀人的执照
A license to kill. Is also a license not to kill.
我这么做也是被迫的
I didn't want to have to do this.
你好像已经控制不了你的特工了
But it looks like you still can't control your agent.
邦德 我帮你查过了
Bond, I ran that check.
貌似是位你曾经交过手的人 量子危机那次
Looks like you've had dealings with him before, Quantum.
果不其然 是怀特先生
Of course, Mr. White!
最近一次现身 是在奥地利的奥尔陶斯
Last unconfirmed sighting, Attersee in Austria.
我再报个名字行吗？
Run another name, will you?
所以实施全面监控看来并非无稽之谈
So, something to be said for total surveillance after all.
你们监控军情六处的探员
You watch MI6 agents?
我们谁都监控
I watch everyone.
您先请坐 我这边很快就完了
Please take a seat. I'll be with you in just a moment.
在周一进行了测试之后 诊断出这位患者患有创伤后应激障碍
Monday, an assessment of post-traumatic diagnostic was done.
开了药物处方 进行大强度的认知行为治疗 同时以颅骶疗法来辅助
Prescribed medicine along with the TCC.
请多包涵 邦德先生
Please excuse me, Mr. Bond.
我是玛德琳·斯旺医生
My name is Dr. Madeleine Swann.
我们今天的任务是分析你的需求 包括心理和身体两个层面
Our job today's to analyze your needs both physiological and physical.
真是开门见山啊
Sounds pretty straight forward.
希望您别介意 这景色容易让人分心
I hope you don't mind, the video can be a bit distracting.
我还没注意到呢
I haven't noticed.
您已经填了大部分的材料
I you've filled out most of the paperwork.
可以的话想问一下剩余的几个问题以完成评估
Just a few questions to complete your evaluation, if I may?
- 你平时锻炼吗？ - 必要时才炼
- You exercise? - When I have to.
你觉得工作给你带来的压力大吗？
You consider employment to be physiologically stressful?
有时候觉得
Sometimes.
一般会喝多少酒？
How much alcohol do you consume?
过量
Too much.
我的问题再放宽点 小时候 你跟你的父母很亲近吗？
Some broader questions: As a child, would you say you were close to your parents?
我从小父母就去世了
My parents died when I was young.
当时几岁？
Really? How old?
- 反正能记事了 - 能问问怎么死的吗？
- Old enough to remember. - How, if I may ask?
- 爬山时发生了意外
A climbing accident.
- 谁把你抚养成人的？ - 是别的人
- Then who brought you up? - Someone else.
我能问问吗？
Humor me.
一位就读过牛津和索邦两所名校
How does one train at Oxford and the Sorbonne
当上顾问 在无国界医生组织工作两年的人
become a consultant, spend 2 years with medicine fortifier
怎么会来到这荒山野岭的地方？
and then end up here?
请恕我冒昧 人家很容易会认为你是在有所回避
Forgive me, but anyone might think you're hiding from something.
您来这儿可是花了不少钱的 邦德先生
You're paying a lot of money to be here, Mr. Bond.
- 到底是我问你啊 还是你问我？ - 当然你问了 请继续
- Who's asking the questions? You or me? - Of course, carry on.
这最后一问你是空着的
I see you left this final question blank.
你做什么职业？
What is your occupation?
这个要是填在表上恐怕会不太好看
Well, that's not the sort of thing that looks good on a form.
- 为什么呢？ - 我的工作是杀人
- And why is that? - I kill people.
这世界多小
Small world, huh?
- 他人在哪里？ - 你父亲去世了 两天前的事
- Where is he? - Your father's dead, two days ago.
- 你怎么知道的？ - 因为我就在现场
- How do you know? - Because I was there.
- 你杀了他？ - 我没那必要
- Did you kill him? - I didn't have to.
他是自杀的
He did it himself.
大老远来就为了告诉我这个？
And you came all the way just to tell me this?
告诉我父亲已经死了？
That my father's dead?
我想说的是你生命有危险 而且我需要你帮助
I came to tell you that your life is in danger and I need your help.
- 为什么？ - 我和他有过约定 要保护你
- Why? - I made a deal with him to protect you.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
- 他凭什么相信你？
Why would he trust you?
因为他也知道我有求于你们
Because he knew that I needed something in return.
- 你想干什么？ - 帮我找到"美国人"
- And what was that? - To find the American.
- 询问结束了 - 斯旺医生
- This interview's over. - Dr. Swann.
给你你10分钟离开这里 然后我会呼叫保安
You have 10 minutes to leave the building, then I'm calling security.
谢谢你 斯旺医生
Thank you, Dr. Swann.
- 想来点什么吗 先生？ - 伏特加马提尼 摇 但别搅拌
- Can I get you something, sir? - Vodka Martini, shaken not stirred.
很抱歉告诉您 我们不提供酒水
I'm sorry, we don't serve alcohol.
我真是越来越喜欢这儿了
I'm already starting to love this place.
给他来一杯含消化酶的奶昔
Can I have the proactive digestive enzyme shake?
没问题
Certainly.
你要是来取车 车已经沉到台伯河底去了
If you've come for the car, I parked it at the bottom of the toilet.
别担心 007 那只是辆价值三百万英镑的概念车
Oh, not to worry, 007. It was only a 3 million pound prototype.
- 你怎么来了 Q？ - 我就是纯粹想休息一下而已
- Why are you here, Q? - Oh, I just fancied a break to be honest
最近工作压力有点大
I've been experiencing a lot of stress recently.
军情五处整天盯着我们
What we see is people crawling all over us and the fact
M也想把我挂在圣诞树上当装饰品
everyone wants my balls for Christmas decorations.
- 说重点 - 007 重点就是 弗朗兹·奥伯豪斯不仅死了
Get to the point - The point, 007, is that Frank Oberhauser is dead.
棺材都下葬了
Dead and buried.
除非你现在就跟我回去
And unless you don't come back right now, my
不然我和莫尼彭尼都前途不保
career and Moneypenny's will go the same way.
你明白吗 现在事态已经全面失控了 你要是不
Do you understand? All hell is breaking loose...
我看见他了
I saw him.
那是你的臆想
You thought you saw him.
我们查阅了所有记录
We've been through the record.
20年前他和他父亲死于一场雪崩
Died in a avalanche, with his father, 20 years...
是
Yes.
这些我都知道 但我的确又见到他了
I know that but I saw him.
我是不可能忘记他的
It's not someone I'd ever forget.
这么说 你有什么头绪吗？
So, you have a lead?
- 有这么个名字 "美国人" - 这就能缩小范围了吗？
I have a name, American. That narrows it down.
对不起 007 先说到这儿吧
Look I'm sorry, 007. Time's up.
我的前途现在悬于一线了
I whole career is on the line here.
要么你现在回去走正常的渠道办事 要么我直接向M报告
Either you come back in and do this through proper channels or I'll go directly to M.
再帮我办件事吧 然后就没你事了
Do one more thing for me, then you're out.
查查这东西的来头
Find out what you can from this.
- 我现在真是恨死你了 - 谢了 Q
- I really, really hate you right now. - Thank you, Q.
- 先生 行了吗？ - 请稍等 你住哪啊？
- Monsieur? Now, please. - Where are you staying?
佩夫斯纳旅馆 12号房 - 一小时后见
At Desner, room 12 - One hour.
您的饮料 先生 一杯热解消化酶奶昔
Here you are, sir. One proactive digestive enzyme shake.
能帮我个忙吗 把这玩意倒厕所里
Do me a favour for me, will you? Thrown that down the toilet.
中间环节都省了
Cut out the middle man.
你待着别动
No, stay!
你们想要什么？
What do you want?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你们都是哑巴吗？
Can any of you speak.
顶住
Come on!
- 好了 快出来 - 别碰我
- Come out. - Aargh, don't touch me!
你应该先好好喘口气 冷静一下情绪
Hey, you need to take a breath and calm down.
- 你是受惊吓了 - 离我远点 给我走开行不行
- You're in shock. - Get away from me! Just get away!
你不觉得是你把他们引来的吗
Did it cross your mind that you lead them to me?!
我现在没时间解释
I haven't got time for this.
你必须告诉我和"美国人"有关的一切细节
You need to tell me everything you know about American.
见鬼去吧
Go to hell!
我向你父亲保证过
I gave your father my word.
我凭什么相信你 就因为我父亲信任你吗？
And why should I trust you? Because my father did?
因为此时此刻 斯旺医生 我是你活下去的唯一机会
Because right now, Dr. Swann. I'm your best chance of staying alive.
斯旺医生 这位是Q  Q 这位是斯旺医生
Dr. Swann, Q. Q, Dr. Swann.
- 你好 - 幸会幸会
- Hello. - Enchanted.
- 邦德 我们俩先谈 不带她 - 她都知道
- Bond, we need to talk. Alone. - She knows.
- 可是 邦德 - 她已经知道了
- But Bond! - She knows.
- 你查到了什么？ - 我得向你道歉 007
- What have you got? - I owe you an apology, 007.
你这回中大奖了
You are on to something.
奥伯豪斯确实还没死 这戒指就是证明
Oberhauser is still alive, the ring proves it.
我搜遍了近五年的工作记录 他们都指向同一个组织
And it seems they were all part of one organization.
拉契夫 量子项目 斯奇亚拉 你的朋友 席尔瓦先生
Le Chiffre, Quantum, Sciarra, your friend, Mr. Silva.
你知道他们都和谁有关联吗？
And do you know who links them all?
- 是他 - 没错就是他(弗朗兹·奥伯豪斯)
- Him. - Exactly.
- 这个神秘组织 知道它叫什么名字吗？ - 不知道
- This organization, do you know what's it called? - No.
"幽灵党"
S.P.E.C.T.R.E.
- 它的名字叫"幽灵党" - 她怎么会知道？
- Its name is SPECTRE. - How does she know that?
因为我父亲就是组织成员
Because my father was part of it.
那么 你应该看看这个
You might all want to see this.
现在切换到南非现场传来的画面 我们能看到的是
Looking at pictures from South Africa right now, is what appears to be...
Q 马上回伦敦去
Q, go back to London.
M需要你的帮助
M's gonna need your help.
然后继续追踪我
Keep tracking me.
我会的 对了 邦德 你一定要找到"美国人"
I will and Bond. You have to find American.
他是找到奥伯豪斯的唯一线索
He's our only link to Oberhauser.
"美国人"不是一个人 那是一个地点
It's not a person, it's a place.
摩洛哥 吉尔丹
谢谢
Thank you.
他俩就在这儿过的新婚之夜
This is where they spent the wedding night.
然后每年都会回来一次
They came back every year.
后来又带着我一起来
Then they brought me with them too.
即使后来都离婚了 父亲一个人还来
He kept coming back, even after the divorce.
那我觉得 太遗憾了
Well, then. I'm sorry.
为什么？
What for?
这是什么？
What is it?
属于你的遗产
It's an inheritance.
- 不来点吗？ - 不了 谢谢
- Want some? - No, thank you.
错过了好事别赖我啊
You don't know what you're missing.
不可能就这么点吧
This can't be it.
算了 先敬你爸一杯
Well, here's to your father.
我答应过我自己 绝不让自己再受到那个男人的伤害
I promised myself, I would never be hurt by that man again.
跟他断了一切联系
I could have hold contact.
我再也不想跟他和他的生活有任何关系
I didn't want to do anything to do with him or his sick life.
而他就在断气之前 却让你来找我
And then with his dying breath, he sends me you.
真讽刺啊 不是吗？
Ironic, no?
你不该对他这么狠
You shouldn't be so hard on him.
他本来早几周前就要死的
And now that I've just mentioned, he would have been dead weeks ago.
硬撑着没咽气就是为了你啊
The reason his heart was still beating was because of you.
我会抽时间去看我的父亲 邦德先生
I mourn my father in my own time, Mr. Bond.
现在我要去睡觉了
And now, I'm going to bed.
休想有一丝邪念 你以为我会因为父亲死了
Don't think for one moment, this is where I fall into your arms.
就会对你投怀送抱 寻求精神慰藉吗？
Seeking solace for my dead daddy.
你给我坐那儿 好好站岗 那是你最擅长的了
You sit there, keep watch. That's what you're good at.
你胆敢靠近我一步 我就杀了你
Come anywhere near me and I will kill you.
这我毫不怀疑
I don't doubt it.
快看 那儿有两个你
Look, there are 2 of you.
有两个詹姆斯 我可真幸运
Two James. Lucky me.
我在这里做什么
致骗子
和杀手
他们无所不在
谁派你来的？
Who sent you?
你在替谁卖命？
Who are you working for?
你到底躲哪儿了？
Now, where did you go?
果然
Of course!
"与维丝帕·林德对谈"
"VESPER LYND INTERROGATION"
那是什么？
What is it?
没设么
Nothing.
这是什么？
What's this?
这些是坐标
Coordinates.
你父亲当时在扫描某个卫星电话 他在找某个人
Your father was scanning for a particular satellite, looking for someone.
他找的是这个人
He was looking for him.
他是让我来完成他的工作
And he sent me here to finish the job.
- 我要跟你一起去 - 不 你别去
- I'm coming with you. - No, you're not.
- 我要你活下去 - 我能照顾好自己
- I'd like you alive. - I can look after myself.
这个并不是重点
That's beside the point.
- 我可能有去无回 - 我知道
- I might not be coming back. - I know.
但我想知道我父亲究竟遭遇了什么
But I want to understand what happened to my father.
说吧 他是去什么地方？
So, where was he going?
不毛之地
Nowhere.
这是怎么回事
What's going on?
会议提前了 你没收到信息吗？
Well a meeting was brought forward, did you not get the message?
根本就没收到
No, we didn't.
- 这是史上最短的会了 - 难道南非也同意了？
- Shortest meeting I can remember. - South Africa's on board.
对 是啊 他们也只能如此了
Yeah, well. Who can blame them?
九只眼协议现在正式生效了
9 Eyes is now officially sanctioned.
新系统72小时内就启动
The new system goes live in less than 72 hours.
这可是向前了一大步
A major step forward.
全球性的情报合作将改变一切
Global Intelligence Corporation changes everythi...
你之前说过了
As, you've said before.
- 听着 他们让我来领导这个委员会 - 当然 然后呢？
Look, they've asked me to hold the new committee - Yes. And?
我得跟你说 我已经跟内政大臣谈过了
And I should tell you I've spoken with the Home Secretary.
鉴于我给他的新信息
And in light of the new information I have given him.
他决定立即停止00特工计划
He's decided to close down the 00 Program with immediate effect.
- 你知道你在做什么吗？ - 不是针对你个人的 那是未来所在
- You don't know what you're doing. - It's not personal. It's the future.
而你
And...
- 你已经过时了 - 你丫不要太狂啊
You're not - You're a cocky little bastard, aren't you?
- 我就当你在夸我 - 想得美
- I'll take that as a compliment. - I wouldn't.
这事儿还没完呢
This isn't over yet.
- 帮我熨下好吗？ - 好的先生
- Will you press this for me? - Yes, sir.
拿起来
Pick it up.
我讨厌枪
I hate guns.
我答应过你爸要保护你的
I promised him I'd protect you.
所以第一件事就是教你保护自己
The first thing to do is to teach you how to protect yourself.
- 我要是误伤了你怎么办？ - 误伤又不是第一次了
- What if I shoot you be mistake? - Wouldn't be the first time.
- 拿起来 - 我说了我讨厌枪
- Pick it up. - I said I hate guns.
这是西格226 前准星 后瞄准器 击锤
SIG-226, front side rear side, hammer.
你只需要瞄准 扣动扳机 尽量不要闭眼
You just point it, squeeze the trigger and try not to close your eyes.
听我的 试试吧
Please, try it.
看来你已经无师自通了啊
I don't have to teach you anything, do I?
曾经有个男的来我家要杀我父亲
A man once came to our house to kill my father.
可他不知道我就在楼上卧室里玩儿
He didn't know I was upstairs playing in my bedroom.
也不知道我爸在水池下藏了一把9毫米的伯莱塔
Papa kept a Beretta 9mm under the sink with the bleach.
所以我特别痛恨枪
That's why I hate guns.
看来也能跳过徒手格斗教学了
I think we'll skip hand-to-hand combat.
晚上好长官 抱歉打断您的晚餐
Evening, sir. Sorry to interrupt your supper.
- 我们刚收到新消息 - 晚上好长官
- But we have some news. - Evening, sir.
通过使用"智能血液" 我们已经追踪到了邦德 他人在北非
Using the Smart Blood, I've tracked Bond to a point here. In North Africa.
- 现在所有地图都指向那片沙漠 - 没错 但您看这儿
The everyday map, registers it as an empty desert - Exactly, but if you look
卫星放大图像却能看到这个
with a satellite blow up, we can clearly see this.
我们帮不了他
I can't help him.
但我们知道他要去哪儿
But, sir. We know where he's heading.
C正监视我们的一举一动 这么做只会给他白送情报
C is watching everything we do. We're only handing them more information.
- 长官 我们不能这样抛弃邦德 - 无能为力 他只能被削弱
- Sir, we can't just desert Bond. - We have to, we only make him weaker.
- 可我们知道他在哪儿啊 - 这我明白
- Sir, you know exactly where he is. - Yes, I know,
我们能追踪他 别人也一样可以
If we can track him, so can others.
给我删除所有"智能血液"相关文件 要不留痕迹
Delete all the Smart Blood files, everything.
他只有靠自己了
He's on his own.
- 盯着多不合适啊 - 天啊 这是同一个人吗
- You shouldn't stare. - Well, you shouldn't look like that.
- 帮你点杯开胃酒吧 - 还没想好呢
- May I get you a cup of tea? - I'm not sure.
我喝酒可会惹麻烦 会让我做出格的事
Gets me into trouble, makes me do crazy things.
- 那样可不行啊 - 所以我就来伏特加马提尼 加点刺激
- Well, we can't have that. - So, I'll have Vodka Martini, dirty.
我也来那个
Make that two.
- 我有个问题 - 什么问题？
- I have a question. - What's that?
为什么有那么多职业可供选择
Why given any other possible option,
偏有人要当职业杀手呢？
does a man choose a life of a paid assassin?
不当杀手 当牧师怎么样？
It was either that or being a priest.
我可是认真的
I'm serious.
这就是你想要的吗？ 整天躲在阴影之中
Is this really what you want? Living in the shadows?
追杀别人 或被别人追杀
Hunting, being hunted.
背后总有人盯着你 一直是孤独一人
Always looking behind you, always alone?
可我并不孤独
No, I'm not alone.
你先回答我的问题
Answer the question.
我不知道自己是否有得可选
I'm not sure I ever had a choice.
但我也不会专门想这个问题
Anyway, I don't stop to think about it.
你如果想了会怎样？
What would happen if you did?
- 专门去想吗？ - 是的
- Stop? - Yes
我不知道
I don't know.
- 这是您的酒 先生 - 请先放那里吧
- Your drinks, sir. - Could you leave them there please?
知道吗 我觉得你错了
You know, I think you're wrong.
我错了吗？
I am?
每个人都会有选择
We always have a choice.
就为这个干一杯
I'll drink to that.
该死
Shit!
现在该干什么
What do we do now?
这样估计要等很久
This might be a long way.
你要不要重新考虑下？
Are you having a second thought?
为时已晚了
Too late now.
那是什么？
What's that?
那车 可是1948年产的劳斯莱斯银魅
That is a 1948 Rolls Royce Silver Wraith.
请上车
Please.
我很害怕 詹姆斯
I'm scared, James.
下午好 邦德先生 斯旺医生
Good afternoon, Mr. Bond. Dr. Swann
终于能见到你们 我们都深感荣幸
I want you to know just how excited we all are to finally meet you.
我们也很高兴能来
Well, it's a pleasure to be here.
主人想请你们先休息放松一下 四点的时候会请你们喝一杯
Your host invites you both to rest, relax and meet him for drinks at 4:00.
- 转告你主人 我们会准时到 - 好极了
- Tell our host, we won't be late. - Wonderful!
带你们去房间前 还有一件事情
Before we show you to your rooms, just one more thing.
你可要小心点
You be careful with that.
它已经上膛了
It's loaded.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是个非常特别的地方
This is a very special place.
主人已要求我们 只能你们独自进去
He has requested, you enter it alone.
没问题
Of course.
来杯香槟吗？
Champagne?
要不再等会儿？
Maybe later.
当然可以
Certainly.
我想我们该表现出惊叹的样子
They say we're meant to be impressed.
摸摸看
Touch it.
你想摸 但摸无妨
Touch it if you want.
- 知道这是什么吗？ - 这是块陨石
- Do you know what it is? - It's a meteorite.
是的 没错
Yes, exactly!
卡腾霍夫 人类已有的最古老陨石
Kartenhoff, the oldest in human possession.
是它在地球上留下了这个陨石坑
The very meteorite that made this crater.
试想一下
Think about it.
先前那么多年里
So many years up there alone, silent.
它是那么孤独而寂静 一直在积聚动能 最终在地球上留下印记
Building momentum until it chose to make its mark on Earth.
它是股不可阻挡的巨大力量
Huge unstoppable force.
但他最终还是停下来了 不是吗？
Except it did stop, didn't it?
停在了这儿
Right here.
你都不知道我期待这一刻有多久了
I can't tell you how much I have been looking forward to this.
我们所有人重聚在一起
All of us here, together.
一个小团圆
A reunion.
很高兴你也来了 亲爱的玛德琳
So glad you came too, dear Madeleine.
我第一次见到你时 你还是个小女孩
You were just a girl, when I saw you first.
有次我去你家找你父亲
I came to your home once to see your father.
我不记得了
I don't remember that.
可我记得
But I do.
请吧
Shall we?
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
和情报有关
Information.
情报就是一切
Information is all.
不是吗？
Is it not?
比如说
For example..
你现在应该知道00计划已经寿终正寝了
You must know by now, that the 00 Program is officially dead.
这让我不禁好奇你为何而来
Which leaves me to speculate, why you came?
我说詹姆斯 你为何而来？
So, James. Why did you come?
我来这是为了杀了你
I came here to kill you.
而我认为你是来送死
And I thought you came here to die.
- 只是看问题的角度不同罢了 - 既然说到看问题的角度
- It's all the matter of perspective. - Speaking of perspective,
- 这是直播吗？ - 实时画面 格林尼治时间十六点二十分
- Is this live? - Live and direct, 16:20 GMT.
真是无巧不成书啊
What an uncanny coincidence.
法语有一句谚语
The French have a saying:
"玻璃的宿命就是破碎"
"It's the faith of glass to break."
看来也许间谍的宿命 就是消失
Well, maybe it's just the faith of spies to just disappear.
不过幸运的是 我们有所成就
But with any luck, we leave something behind.
与此同时 C会继续出色领导大家的工作
In the meantime, I'm sure C will keep you all busy.
谢谢大家
Thank you all.
真是感人 你不觉得吗？
It's touching, don't you think?
可惜啊詹姆斯
Poor old, James.
你成了被遗忘的角落
It looks like you're all alone.
你难道只是个偷窥狂吗？
Not much more than a bore are you?
胆小到不敢加入我们
Too scared to join in?
- 看来你还没明白 - 不 我很明白
- I don't think you quite understand. - I think I do.
你策划那几个城市的袭击 伤及无辜 就是逼人就范
You set cities on fire, watch innocent people burn so you can convince
让那些政府加入你操盘的情报网络
governments to join the intelligence network you paid for.
整件事并不复杂
Not that complicated
我猜我们的小朋友C 他该是你的门徒之一吧
I'm guessing out little friend, C, is one of your disciples?
就算是吧
You could say that.
他会得到什么好处？
What does he get out of it?
什么都没有
Nothing?
- 他和我都能看得很远 - 看得远的人
- He's a visionary, like me. - Visionary, I see.
精神病院里多的是
Psychiatry wards are full of them.
而你连眼前都看不清
Where as you can see what's right in front of you.
我们交手那么多次 你却从来没发现过我
You came across me so many times and yet you never saw me.
- 拉契夫 格林 席尔瓦 - 他们都死了
- Le Chiffre, Greene, Silva... - All dead.
没错
That's right.
你我之间有种模式
A nice pattern developed, you interfere
你侵犯我的世界 我就毁掉你的世界
my world, I destroy yours.
你觉得你生命中所有女人最后都死了是种巧合吗？
Or did you think it was coincidence that all the women in your life ended up dead?
就拿维斯帕·林德来说
Vesper Lynd, for example.
这位算是举足轻重的吧 他没跟你说起过吗？
She was the big one, has he told you about her?
当然还有这位 你最亲爱的M夫人
An then of course, your beloved M.
也永远离开了你
Gone forever.
是我
Me...
全都是我干的 詹姆斯
It was always me, James.
这些都源于我 你所有痛苦都是我写就的
It's always been me. The author of all your pain.
你是个勇敢的女人 亲爱的
You're a brave woman, my dear.
我终于明白我父亲为什么会疯了
Now I understand why my father lost his mind.
他没有疯 他就是软弱
He didn't lose his mind, he was just weak.
但他起码知道他是在与谁为敌
But at least he understood, what he was up against.
他们不能理解的一个残酷事实是
Comprehended a crucial fact that.
一个可怕的事件也会催生完美的事物
A terrible event, can lead to something wonderful.
既然说到你父亲 不妨让你也看看
Since you mentioned you father, I'll show you.
她相当聪明 她比我聪明 知道怎么躲起来
She's clever, she's smarter than me. She knows how to hide.
说出那人在哪 我就能保护你女儿
And I'm going to protect her if you tell me where he is.
- 我能保住她的命 - 好啊
- I can keep her alive. - Yeah.
You have my word - I can keep her alive. Yeah.
我向你承诺
You have my word.
不不不 快关掉
No, no, no, no, no. Turn this off.
你向我承诺？
Word?
一个杀手也能信？
The word of an assassin?
马上给我关掉
Turn this off!
- 这一段很重要 - 我说了马上关掉
- This is important. - I said turn it off!
我想让你明白一件事
I want you to understand something.
说到做到
That's my word
玛德琳
Madeleine.
看着我
Look at me.
别看他 玛德琳 看着我
Don't look at him, Madeleine. Look at me.
"美国人"
American.
你只要能救她 她就能带你去"美国人"那儿 她非常了解
You save her, she can lead you to the American. She knows the American.
先去霍夫勒诊所看看
Try the Chauffeur Clinic.
你现在就是只风筝 在飓风中飞舞的风筝 邦德先生
You're a kite dancing in a hurricane, Mr. Bond.
永别了
So long.
那些能把人聚到一起的事情
Things that bring people together.
也许是恐惧 也许是美
Out of horror, beauty.
肉体折磨太简单了 流于肤浅
Torture is an easy and efficient way.
一个人可以看着自己被开膛
A man can watch himself being disemboweled.
从中会产生出巨大恐惧
Surprise brings horror to the experience.
但这种折磨远未触及其灵魂
It can go over a distance, it isn't taking
仍没有触及到他的真正内心
place where he is.
你应该很清楚 亲爱的玛德琳
You know all too well, my dear Madeleine.
真正的他存在于他的大脑之中
A man lives inside his head.
那里才安放着他的灵魂
That's where the seed of the soul is.
最近我和詹姆斯同时目睹一个人刚被挖去双眼
James and I were both present recently. When a man was deprived of his eyes.
接着一件最令人震惊的事情发生了
And the most astonishing thing happened, didn't you notice?
你注意到了吗？ 他的灵魂已经不在了
He wasn't there anymore.
他虽然还活着 可灵魂已死
He's gone even though, he's alive.
就在生与死的那一瞬间
This brief moment between life and death.
他脑海里再没有任何人
There was nobody inside his skull.
真是奇妙
Most odd.
那么 詹姆斯
So, James.
我现在要渗透进你的大脑
I'm going to penetrate to where you are.
去触及你的灵魂所在 探索你的脑部世界
To the inside of you head.
这第一根探针会玩弄你的视觉 你的听觉
The first probe will play with your sight.
还有平衡感
Curing your balance.
- 只需要最轻微的操作即可 - 那你就尽管来吧
- Just with a subtlest manipulation. - Get on with it then.
没什么能比听你啰嗦更痛苦了
Nothing can be as painful as listening to you talk.
那好吧
Alright.
我们开始
Let's begin!
你为什么要这么做？
Why are we doing this?
你应该知道 詹姆斯很小的时候就失去了双亲
You probably know that, James here lost his parents when he was young.
但你知道吗 后来是我父亲 陪他度过最艰难的时光
But did you know that it was my father who helped him out through his difficult times?
一连两个冬天 我父亲教他滑雪 教他登山 还有打猎
Over the course of 2 winters, he taught him to ski, climb and hunt.
他为这位蓝眼珠的可怜孤儿抚平了心灵创伤
He soothe the wound of the poor little blue eyed orphan.
还让我把他当做自己的兄弟
Asked me to treat him as a brother.
把他当做小弟弟看
My little brother.
我们之间结下了深厚情谊
They formed quite an attachment.
所以 你选择把他杀了
No, you killed him.
没错 那是我干的
Yes, I did.
你们应该能猜到 布谷鸟为了在别的鸟巢产卵会怎么做
You know what happens when a Cuckoo hatches inside another bird's nest?
- 我知道 它会把别的蛋推出巢外 - 没错
- It's forced to steal the eggs out. - Yes.
所以 这只布谷鸟让我意识到我的父亲必须死
Well, this Cuckoo made me realize my father's life had to end.
可以说 我的所作所为是他逼的
In a way, he's responsible for the path I took.
所以谢谢你 布谷
So, thank you. Cuckoo!
能来点别的鸟叫吗？ 弗朗兹
Do you know any bird calls, Franz?
你好 猫咪
Hello, pussy.
弗朗兹·奥伯豪斯20年前就死了
Franz Oberhauser died 20 years ago, James.
他跟他父亲 同时死于一场雪崩
In an avalanche, alongside his father.
现在跟你说话的人 你脑子里想的这个人
The man you're talking to now, the man inside your head.
叫恩内斯特·史戴弗·布鲁夫尔德
Is Ernst Stavro Blofeld.
- 大有来头？ - 承袭自我母亲家族那边
- Fancy name? - My mother's bloodline.
探针要是在脑内梭状回里扎对了地方
If the needle finds the correct spot in the circumvolutia spindle.
你就谁也不认识了
You'll recognize no one.
当然 你那些女人的脸互相换来换去也无妨
Of course, if this even changes a lot, huh, James.
你会连她都不认识的
You won't know who she is.
她只是你前往坟墓途中 看到的一张脸而已
Just another passing face on your way to the grave.
他临死的时候会根本认不出你
He dies not knowing who you are.
一个杀手的女儿 唯一能真正理解他的人
The daughter of an assassin, the only one who could have understood.
可惜了
Shame.
我爱你
I love you.
那对蓝眼珠还认得出你吗？
Do those blue eyes still recognize you?
到哪儿我都能认出你
I'd recognize you anywhere.
我的手表
Watch.
1分钟之后
One minute.
只剩1分钟
他说什么了吗？
Did you say something?
光阴似箭
I guess you did.
- 什么？ - 光阴 似箭
- What? - Doesn't time fly...
听不见 詹姆斯
I can't hear you, James.
我说 真是时光飞逝啊
I said, "doesn't time fly"?
去那边
There!
我们该回家了
Let's go home.
这事儿还没完呢
It's not over yet.
- 我没听说过希尔德布兰德 - 这样才叫安全堡垒啊
- Nobody's ever heard of Hildebram. - That is the general idea of safe houses.
- 这里能有多安全？ - 很快就能知道了
- Exactly how safe is this house? - We're about to find out.
果然安全 你们在这等着
It's safe. A bit of wait.
- 我是M - 玛德琳·斯旺
- I'm M. - Madeleine Swann.
很高兴见到你 007 你有什么新消息？
Pleased to meet you. So, what do you have for me, 007?
最近死亡的幽灵党头目 恩内斯特·史戴弗·布鲁夫尔德
The recently deceased head of SPECTRE, Ernst Stavro Blofeld
以及他的情报部长 你的新搭档C
and chief of intelligence, your new best friend, C.
马上就要接管他在我们眼皮子底下建的
Were about to take control of his very own global surveillance system that he built.
- 那个强大的全球监控体系了 - 那最好抓紧时间
- Right here, in our own houses. - Then we'd better move.
系统午夜就要启动了
The system goes online at midnight.
他们要是得逞 幽灵党就会掌控一切
If that happens SPECTRE will have control of everything.
你和我去会一会C
So, you and I will have a quiet word with C. While Q
同时Q侵入系统 组织系统上线
hacks into the system and stops it getting online.
- 那可不容易 - 他会有办法的
- It won't be easy. - He'll find a way.
他一向如此
He always does.
- 欢迎你归队 007 - 长官
- It's good to have you back 007 - Sir.
- 詹姆斯 我办不到 - 我会回来找你的
- James, I can't. - I'll come back for you.
- 等这一切结束之后 - 不 我做不到
- When it's all over. - I know I can't.
- 你是不能待在这儿 还是 - 我不能再过这种生活
- You can't stay here or...? - I can't go back to this life.
我也不想让你做出改变
And I'm not doing to ask you to change.
你就是这种人
This is who you are.
- 你是要跟我告别？ - 是的
- You're saying goodbye. - Yes.
你保重
Take care.
你是个好人 詹姆斯
You're a good man, James.
黑进去了吗 Q？
Are you in yet, Q?
还有好几层难搞的防火墙
Few layers of impenetrable layers to go but I think
但我应该是有些进展了
I'm getting somewhere.
- 他们看见我们了 - 倒车
- They've seen us. - Move back!
走
Go!
把他带进楼去
Get into the building!
快走啊 走啊
Move. Move!
快回去找到M 马上 两个都要抓到
Go back and find M, now! We need them both.
被人监视的感觉不好吧
Not a good feeling being watched, is it?
别告诉我这是你捣的鬼
Don't tell me you're responsible for this.
哪有 是我的军需官Q
No, but my quartermaster is.
他可不是一般的才华横溢
And he's extremely talented.
做得漂亮 可你们没有意识到 你们已经被炒了
Bravo, but in case you haven't realized it. You two are out of a job.
- 所以 你现在算是非法闯入 - 恐怕是你错判局势了 麦克斯
So you're trespassing - I'm afraid you've got the wrong end of the stick, Max.
我们要阻止系统上线
We're going to stop this system going online.
- 还要把你也送进去 - 未免无凭无据吧
- Then I'm going to bring you in. - On what grounds exactly?
就凭你交友不慎
Poor taste in friends.
放眼看看这个世界
Take a look at the world.
一片混乱
Chaos!
因为有像你这样的人
Because people like you.
层层官僚和政客们才会毫无担当 终日无所作为
People pushes, politician are too spineless to deal which what needs to be done.
所以我跟其他人结成联盟 要让权力能物尽其用
So, I made an alliance to put the power where it should be.
现在你们打着民主政治的旗号 想让它胎死腹中
And now you want to throw it away for the sake of democracy.
这是何等荒唐
Whatever the hell that is.
令人费解 愚钝之极
How predictably moronic.
但这不就是M毕生的使命吗？
But then isn't that what M stands for?
愚蠢
Moron?
那我们现在也清楚C先生的使命了
Now you know what C stands for.
太大意了
Careless.
拜托
Come on!
不 不 不
No, no, no!
你还真是一只不死鸟啊
You're a hard man to kill, Blofeld.
但愿没让你疼得太厉害
I do hope that doesn't hurt too much.
我的伤口会愈合的
Oh, my wounds will heal.
可你的伤口呢？
What about yours?
看看四周吧 詹姆斯 你的世界就剩下这些
Look around, James. Look! This is what's left of your world.
你所代表的一切 你所信仰的一切 都化作乌有
Everything you ever stood for, everything you believed in. A ruin.
我们干嘛在这儿？
Why am I here?
- 你想我了？ - 并没有
- Did you miss me? - No.
但我知道有人想你了
But I know someone who does!
- 她人在哪儿？ - 那得靠你去找了
- Where is she? - That's for you to find out.
三分钟后 这座大楼会被夷为平地
Three minutes, this building will be demolished.
我轻易就能离开
Well, I can get out easily.
而你得做出抉择
But you have a choice.
是豁出命去救她
Die trying to save her, or.
还是 自己保命活在痛苦之中
Save yourself and live with the pain.
你在虚张声势
You're bluffing.
我有吗？
Am I?
我让你左右为难了吧？
I've really got you now haven't I?
谁让我是你兄弟呢？
Oh, that's rather sweet.
太了解如何操纵你了
They always know which button to press.
玛德琳
Madeleine!
拜托 拜托
Come on, come on.
好的
Yes!
- 走吧 - 你先请
Let's go. After you.
为什么不正视现实 M？
Why can't you just face it, M?
- 你没有存在价值了 - 我也许是没有
- You don't matter anymore. - Maybe I don't.
但有些必须有
But something has to.
- 死了 - 有邦德的消息吗？
- Dead. - Any word on Bond?
没有 但我可以猜得到
No, but I'm starting to guess.
玛德琳
Madeleine!
- 你相信我吗？ - 我还有选择吗？
- Do you trust me? - Do I have a choice?
想都别想
Not anymore.
快点儿
Come on!
别了 詹姆·斯邦德
Goodbye, James Bond.
- 先生 这里是管制区域 - 马洛里 00计划部的
- Sir, there's a terrorist alert. - Mallory, 00 Section.
解除戒备
Stand them down.
E组 都别开火 解除戒备
The Go Team hold. Stand down.
了结了吧
Finish it.
快了结了吧
Finish it!
没有子弹
Out of bullet.
而且现在 我还有更重要的事情要办
And besides, I've got something better to do.
根据2001年的《特殊措施法案》
Under the special measures act of 2001
我代表英国政府正式拘捕你
I'm detaining you on behalf of Her Majesty's government.
邦德
Bond?
- 你来这儿做什么？ - 早安 Q
- What are you doing here? - Good morning, Q.
- 我以为你走了呢 - 是啊
- I thought you'd gone. - I had.
但我还缺一样东西
There's just one thing I need.